[SPEAKER_00]: I was thinking maybe you have something in mind, since you don't get to come here often.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll be listening.
[SPEAKER_00]: Unless you want to just hear me ask.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that would be alright.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's been asking the last two days.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, one thing I was just curious about, how your interpretation of a certain sutta, this is from the Sanyuktinikāya, second Khandhasamyukta.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the one where the Buddha compares form to a lump of foam, feelings to bubble.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember that one?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So,
[SPEAKER_00]: For example, one of the stanzas says, bhikkhu, suppose this river Ganges was carrying a great long, great lump of foam.
[SPEAKER_00]: A man with good sight would inspect it, ponder it, and carefully investigate it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it would appear to him to be void, hollow, and substantial.
[SPEAKER_00]: For what substance could there be in a lump of foam?
[SPEAKER_00]: So too, bhikkhus, whatever kind of form there is, whether past, future, or present, internal or external, gross or subtle, inferior or superior, far or near,
[SPEAKER_00]: Bhikkhu inspects it, ponders it, and carefully investigates it, and it would appear to him to be void, hollow, or insubstantial.
[SPEAKER_00]: For what substance could there be in form?
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, this is just a translation.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know off the top of my head what the exact Pali word is for void, hollow, insubstantial.
[SPEAKER_00]: Inspect.
[SPEAKER_00]: Inspect, as well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Pali word is for that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can, I can look up to Pali, if you'd like me to.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it's okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, I don't know if it's just a translation, but to me, it makes it sound like that kind of, you know, emptiness form, form is emptiness kind of thing, where form doesn't actually exist.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just a lump, like a foam.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's no center to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, that's the thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nobody says it doesn't exist.
[SPEAKER_01]: It just means it's hollow and void in its existence.
[SPEAKER_01]: It doesn't mean you denial the actual appearance of the bubble, of the foam.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you recognize the nature of that which is, well, very, very transient, so to speak, without any, any everlasting substance.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, you recognize the same characteristics in this very foam.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that doesn't, that doesn't mean that, that the whole thing does not exist.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which is, that's exactly like what you, what you have
[SPEAKER_01]: What you have just said, the emptiness form is emptiness.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, that's true, in a general sense, but now, what would a person mean by that?
[SPEAKER_01]: And often, they mean denial, denial of things.
[SPEAKER_01]: Emptiness, that means it's not real, it's not there.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, it is there, as empty.
[SPEAKER_01]: If there's nothing there, you can't distinguish even emptiness.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, if nothing is there, there's absolutely no reference point for full or empty, the substance or no substance.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, it is very real,
[SPEAKER_01]: But it's fleeting.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's non-substantial, so to speak.
[SPEAKER_01]: But as such, it is real.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's why you recognize that and then you apply the same to your form, to the form that pertains to the sense of self.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because sense of self cannot be established upon that which is fleeting and non-substantial and void and hollow and transient.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, applying that to that upon which your sense of self depends, undermines the sense of self, but leaves the bubbles of the foam intact.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were always that.
[SPEAKER_01]: What has changed is your attitude in regard to them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Appropriation, they used to exist upon the assumption that there is substance to it, there is the actual ground for the self.
[SPEAKER_01]: That has changed.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's gone and then there's appropriation constant.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the same thing applies then for the rest of the similes, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_00]: The perceptions like an illusion.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, for all the aggregates, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Inventions like a plantain.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, see that whole thing like, oh, it's an illusion.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can regard it, it's an illusion.
[SPEAKER_01]: But again, that doesn't mean that it's not real as such.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nobody in the society doesn't say it does not exist.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's an illusion and it does not exist.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yet, when you say illusion, and maybe that's because of all of the other
[SPEAKER_01]: Schools of Buddhism or other religious practices, people nowadays, you say illusion, that means like, oh, it's not real.
[SPEAKER_01]: But illusion is real.
[SPEAKER_01]: If it weren't real, you wouldn't be ignorant in the first place.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's real as such.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's basically illusion means it's different to what you think it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you're deluded by it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when that changes, that
[SPEAKER_01]: Which, you were deluded by in the beginning, still remains.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, what has changed is your delusion about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the thing remains.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, the essay, dharmata-sacca.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't want to do that, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't want to be resisted.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't want to be resisted.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're not the actual dharmata-sacca.
[SPEAKER_00]: The last one, which I don't know if I have always thought too far into it, but even this one,
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, there are works that go very deep into detail into it, whether they're right or wrong.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, you know, those Magic of the Mind, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of his books, where he compares consciousness to a magician's show.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's saying, suppose that a magician or a magician's apprentice would display a magical illusion at the crossroads.
[SPEAKER_00]: A man with bits I wouldn't expect would ponder so-and-so and so forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: And same thing for consciousness now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, it's...
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you think this similes to me, just as saying that, yeah, it's, you know, not substantial, this consciousness, like you're saying, form?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or is there more, eh... descending from that simile, like, oh, it's like a deceptive, or it's misleading, or something?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, yeah, you can, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, you can say that, basically.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's, eh... You... You have misled yourself with assumptions in regard to consciousness.
[SPEAKER_01]: Eh...
[SPEAKER_01]: So...
[SPEAKER_01]: The magician's performance, if that's the simile, it's real as such.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a magician's performance.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is what he's done.
[SPEAKER_01]: But your belief upon it, depends on you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the most basic deception, the most basic misconception, is regarding permanent that which is impermanent, regarding pleasurable that which is suffering, and then taking that thing to be yourself, which you cannot be.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's like the fundamental
[SPEAKER_01]: So, there's... is there no problem in people regarding, oh, this is all illusion?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, as long as you don't blame things for that illusion, but blame your own attitude towards it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But usually, whenever I've heard, oh, illusion, illusion, it was said in a dismissive sense, whereby, oh, this is all illusion, this is all not real, there is no problem, there is no nibbāna, there is nothing which is already a nibbāna, which is everything and nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just become having all sorts of use, because it's just blanket denial of everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: But sure, illusion is real as such.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, stop being deluded by that illusion and see through what it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: And what it is, it's impermanent suffering, thus it cannot be taken from yourself.
[SPEAKER_01]: It cannot be taken to belong to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bubbles will... and the foam will keep arising for as long as there is a river foaming and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: But when the river drains up, even the aggregates break apart, that's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's part of the environment and they will not arise again.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not even those illusory bubbles.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another question I have is that you mentioned of internal-external a lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was hoping that we could clarify exactly those terms.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, I know it's kind of a broad question, but in general, you know, the Buddhadharma science says internal-external, both internal-external, like even satipaṭṭhāna and citta.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I guess the question
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm trying to figure out, it's like, internal it to what?
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, what is, what defines internal versus external?
[SPEAKER_00]: And is that, if it's, if it's, you know, the first thing that comes to mind is, so, internal is mine, external is not.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then the question is, is it valid to look at things like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Usually, yeah, there is a degree of mine associated with internal dimension.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, again, broadly speaking, because it is a broad question, and internally, externally, sometimes, using not always the same sense, as, as, and I think Nirmala said, basically, internal would be everything that pertains to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, externally, it would be everything that doesn't pertain to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, that's like the broadest, broadest distinction.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, obviously, fundamentally,
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, for an Arahant, for example, there is this conscious body left and all the name and form external.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you can see that that which used to be his, like this conscious body, it doesn't say, oh, the conscious body is left internally for an Arahant and name and form external.
[SPEAKER_01]: It says, what is left is this conscious body and name and form external.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, in that sense, when internal means mine, that is gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, now, that which used to be taken as mine is still there, but it's not internal in that personal sense, because more often than not, that which pertains to oneself is what is one's, what he has appropriated.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thus, internal and mine do become almost interchangeable when it comes to the attitude of people, but they don't need to be, obviously.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, when the Buddha says something like, kāyā kāyāṁ paśyati, like, mindful of the body, in terms of, or in the body, however you want to translate it, internally, externally, whatever, you're saying that it's a question of, like, seeing one's present attitude of taking the body as mine, meaning myself, but being mindful of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Otherwise... Well, you can... that, that, in sattvipaṭṭhānasutra, basically means, you can, if you take it
[SPEAKER_01]: If you're mindful of the body internally, you're mindful from the point of view of this conscious body here, you can be mindful of the same body externally, if you approach it from the point of view of nāmarūpa, which is external, even if it's looking at your own body.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you always have two points of view at the same time.
[SPEAKER_01]: That is the, that is the, like, the fundamentals of every human experience, or the experience of the five aggregates.
[SPEAKER_01]: And because you have two points of view, there can't be one sent to them, one owner of them, because they are simultaneously arising independent of each other.
[SPEAKER_01]: This conscious body, name and form externally.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, if you are seeing a body in the experience of the name and form externally, that body is external body.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you're attending to the body on the aspect of this conscious body right here, because of which I have this experience as a whole, that is the internal body.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, your same distinction is like internal would be like my sense of what my body is, like the idea of my body.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, for example, I'm mindful of my body seated, but not because I'm seeing it, but because I know it's seated.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would be the external.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's external, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be external.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't understand what internal means.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Internal dimensions
[SPEAKER_01]: It's the dimension whereby, if you obviously attend it externally, it's not the internal dimension.
[SPEAKER_01]: The internal dimension is the conscious body right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because of which, you can doubt what the internal dimension right here is.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's because the internal dimension is already there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, it's not accessible.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's accessible only through discernment, so to speak.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which is why, if you discern it, you can't appropriate it anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can only appropriate it when you don't know what it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, it's mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, this vague notion of internal is a notion of mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: When it's discerned, when there is no ignorance in regard to it, there is no mine in regard to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thus, for an ārahant, it's just this conscious body and name and form externally.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't get it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, no, I know, I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is it the consciousness is constantly flooding inside you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Doesn't appear.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I guess, it's the negative.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can say that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, it appears as a negative, but yeah, if you make it positive, then it just becomes positive, which is not this, this conscious body.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's there, it's external.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the external, name and form, is because of that which external name and form has here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can say that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's what I mean when I say that, in a way, everything is external to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, nothing can be mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, if you... if you wanna... if you wanna... if you start... if a person starts practicing this passion, then the result will be
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, what is taken to be internal, as mine, and then the opposing world external, well, those components, so to speak, remain.
[SPEAKER_01]: But what changes is the attitude in regard to them.
[SPEAKER_01]: So now, you really... it becomes more accurate to say there is external, external, and there is the less external, which used to be internal.
[SPEAKER_00]: Does the internal sense of one's body appear?
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, is it... Well, if it appears, it appears on the level of nāmarūpa.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as such, it's external, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Obviously, for a patujana, when all that is taken as mind, he takes it, like nāmarūpa to be his, and whatever pertains to his body, so it's all a mess, obviously.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, yeah, if it is designated into a phenomenon, positive phenomenon, then it's nāmarūpa, then it is external as such.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right, because I've understood your statement to some degree in the past, where it's like the body that you can't directly access, but that by which there is feeling, consciousness, whatever.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, you cannot access that directly through feeling, consciousness, perception, because it precedes them structurally.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you can discern that this body, that you do see externally, as a part of nāmarūpa, when it arises and such, is that because of which, because of which presence, right here and now, this whole experience is in the first place?
[SPEAKER_01]: And is that presence, right here and now, it's what this conscious body is?
[SPEAKER_00]: So, perhaps, one could say, then, that an internal sense of one's body is kind of like... like consciousness.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like negative.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is negative.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because this conscious body, it comes in a bundle.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't separate one from the other.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't conceive, even investigate consciousness apart from the form of body.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nor can you even, even, even ponder on the notion of body if there is no consciousness in regard to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But what happens is, with the appropriation, then, whatever resembles this conscious body, it just ends up being piled up on top of that negative phenomenon.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, it becomes quite positive.
[SPEAKER_01]: The positive internal of a putujana, which, for him, is mine.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, in that sense, internal... perhaps the designation is always a designation, but it depends on how one regards the designation.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's important.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would you agree?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Designation is whenever the problem is.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, people think designation is a problem and they try not saying I, or I am, or I will, because, you know, there is no self.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was happening to the Buddha.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, no, the Thalitta still uses those words, those terms, but he knows them as mere designations.
[SPEAKER_01]: And for him, that does not stand for the actual sense of self.
[SPEAKER_00]: This question came out yesterday.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were down there, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was yesterday?
[SPEAKER_01]: Day before.
[SPEAKER_00]: Day before.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mentioned thoughts.
[SPEAKER_00]: All your thoughts are external.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why people could potentially, you know, read your thoughts, if they have that power.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so, that got me thinking, like, how could that be?
[SPEAKER_01]: So, that means, basically, that thoughts that are internal, for somebody who's developed their mind, become just less external than things that are externally external for everyone.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, that's what I mean.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those thoughts don't change from the internal domain where they are.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't go out into the external where everybody can see them.
[SPEAKER_01]: They stay where they are.
[SPEAKER_01]: But what changes is the mind in regard to these domains.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, you can see other people's thoughts.
[SPEAKER_01]: They are not aware of it, obviously, because for them, it's gripped by the whole pile-up of internal mind dimension, which they just regard
[SPEAKER_01]: It's hidden, but it's actually out there and it can be seen from from the way they would speak, act, behave.
[SPEAKER_01]: All of these thoughts as possibilities become discerned as external to somebody whose mind has been developed with regard to more domains.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're just part of nāma, rūpa and sañña things too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it seems that the idea of them being internal comes as though they're in my brain.
[SPEAKER_00]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're placed in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's exactly... You look at the foam, the bubble, and there's nothing you can place in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It has a reason as such, and it will go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Same goes for every single organ, every single part of your body.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's exactly it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It has no substance.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing can be placed in it that is substantial.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, that's why people need to keep pondering on this, to stop associating any notions of mine as in me, in this brain, in this body, in this heart.
[SPEAKER_01]: Consciousness is in here.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: These things are inaccessible to any such placements.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're mere bubbles.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's nothing to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they're still phenomena.
[SPEAKER_01]: As such, exactly, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which is why people get confused.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why they can maintain this misconception.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because these things keep arising, and the misconception keeps persisting, because nobody undoes it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, the rūpa in name and form, nāmarūpa, that's still external form, because it's name and form with tāngra.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not that internal sense.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it's not that particular rūpa because of which there are sāryasāṃsmādhi statues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just the rūpa in the ultimate kind of general sense.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there are certain matter, there is certain matter around the domain of matter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because of which, there is the arising of sights, sounds, smell.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's your eyes, your tongue, your ears.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_01]: When, when consciousness is there juxtaposed with that matter, and that whole relationship precedes you entirely, you can't even access it in your thoughts or abstraction.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doesn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Only through like that negative direction of discernment, which is what discernment is.
[SPEAKER_00]: You need the eye working and a form.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't just have one or the other.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mentioned also in previous talks this idea of consciousness being external, like with the object.
[SPEAKER_01]: With that form.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not necessarily with... well, with the material aspect of the object, not with the actual object.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because the object is the result of consciousness and form already being there just the pose.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right.
[SPEAKER_00]: My experience of an object is different from the material of an object.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you can't say that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because that comparison will imply you somehow accessing the the relationship between consciousness and the object and then inferring that they're different.
[SPEAKER_01]: But saying that it's the same...
[SPEAKER_01]: It's conceivable.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Saying it's the same, different, both same and different, neither same or different, makes no sense, because all of those, either of those, would require you accessing that which you can't.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thus, people maintaining notions that this is the same, or this is what the matter is, or this is different from matter, or this is in the matter, or matter is in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: All of those things are conceivings.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you can't have the second part of that relationship for which you would need.
[SPEAKER_01]: to have access in order to make all these conceivings.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's where they're wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even if, say, miraculously, they correspond to how things are, that doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you can't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you can't access how things are.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thus, you conceiving them to be in a certain way, will always be a misrepresentation.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's interesting to think about the idea of accessibility versus not being accessible.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not something you... Not accessible, but there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you don't access... you stop trying to conceive the access when the designation there does not move towards it, so to speak, in any direction, does not try to access it, even by implication.
[SPEAKER_01]: When the mind is fully developed in regard to it,
[SPEAKER_01]: Then it stops being a conceiving of that because of which the mind is there in the first place.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, so it's like taking up what's not accessible, trying to...
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yeah, that's what conceiving is.
[SPEAKER_01]: Taking up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just, just by leaning too much or leaning a bit away from.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or assuming that it's in, out, both in and out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Neither in or out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Assuming that it's onward.
[SPEAKER_01]: Assuming that it's accessible.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why the Mūla Pāryāya Sutta just
[SPEAKER_01]: And it goes around all of the different objects.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because it's not what you are conceiving.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's the actual attitude of conceiving.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the root of the problem.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it's important then to realize that the object being there comes prior to whatever assumptions you could make about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, structurally prior, not temporarily prior.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, it's simultaneously present, but it structurally precedes it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The structure of movement, the notion of movement, is preceded by it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you can't then access it as a result of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Structural space as well.